George W. Henry Foundation and the Canon Clinton Jones Archive 1933-1986 (bulk 1963-1986) GLBTQ.2010.01
GLBTQ Archives, Central Connecticut State University
George W. Henry Foundation/ Canon Clinton Jones Archive
1933-1986
GLBTQ.2010.01
GLBTQ Archives, Central Connecticut State University
10.0 Linear feet
George W. Henry Foundation.
Jones, Clinton R
Historical Note
In 1963, the members of the Social Service Department of the Greater Hartford Council of Churches formed the Rehabilitation Committee which evolved into the ad hoc Project "H" Committee. Its first task was to study the subject of homosexuality. During this study period, the committee became aware of the George W. Henry Foundation which was chartered in the state of New York in 1947. It had been founded "to help those who by reason of sexual deviation were in trouble with themselves." Dr. Albert Gross who was heading this foundation was invited to Hartford to discuss his work. Out of that meeting, the group became the Hartford Chapter of the George W. Henry Foundation in 1965.Since education was a major thrust of the Committees' work, members were involved in lecturing, counseling, in workshops, in panel discussions and in organizing conferences and symposiums.
With the retirement of the Reverend Canon Clinton Jones, officials of Christ Church Cathedral decided they were unable to afford a counselor to continue Reverend Jones' work. By the time of his retirement in the late 1980's, dozens of groups had come into existence to serve the needs of the gay and lesbian community. For many years, the Committee on Sexual Minorities and its predecessors was the only organization that people were able to turn to for help.
Biographical Note
Clinton Robert Jones was born Nov. 8, 1916 in Manchester, Connecticut, the son of Robert Jones and Henriette Elizabeth (Morehouse). Canon Jones received his BA in 1938 and DD in 1966 from Bard College. He received his masters of divinity in 1941 from the General Theological Seminary in New York. In 1969 he received his S.T.M. from the New York Theological Seminary. He was curate at St. James Church in New London, Connecticut between 1941 - 1945, vicar at St. James Church, Poquetanuck, CT and Episcopal chaplain at Connecticut College for Women during the same period. He served as chaplain between 1945 and 1946 of the United States Maritime Service, Assistant Minister of Christ Church Cathedral, Hartford, CT. 1946 - 1948 and Canon of Christ Church Cathedral 1948 until his retirement in 1986.
DIOCESAN ACTIVITIES
Member - Dept. of Christian Education 1942 - 1967
Director of Youth 1946 - 1953
Member - Diocesan Executive Council 1953 - 1961
Member - Diocesan Standing committee 1965 - 1970
Member - Commission on Ministry 1969 - 1972
Chairman - Diocesan Committee on Human Sexuality 1976 - 1983
Member - Diocesan Committee on Health and Human Services 1983 - 1986
NATIONAL CHURCH ACTIVITIES
Member - National Youth Commission 1947 - 1951
Member - The Task Force on the Church and the Homophile of the house of Bishops 1972 - 1975
COMMUNITY RELATIONSHIPS
Chairman - Committee on Religion and Health of the Greater Hartford Council of Churches 1963 - 1969
Member - Committee on Sexual Minorities - Greater Hartford Council of Churches 1964 - 1986
Trustee Bard College 1955 - 1961
Associate Trustee, Bard College 1961 -
Chaplain - Hartford Chapter, Guild of St. Barnabas for Nurses 1951 -
National Chaplain, St. Barnabas Guild for Nurses 1961 - 1967; 1983 -
Officer - Board of the New England Gender Identity Clinic 1972 -
National Secretary - The Harry Benjamin International Association on Gender Dysphoria 1985 - 1987
ADVISORY BOARDS
The Janus Information Facility, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, Texas 1977 - 1980
Transition: A Confide Publication, Tappan, New York 1978
Integrity Forum - Chicago, Illinois 1979 -
Metamorphosis Magazine - Toronto, Canada 1983 -
PUBLICATIONS
Books: What About Homosexuality? Thomas Nelson and Co. 1972
Homosexuality and Counseling. Fortress Press 1974
Understanding Gay Relatives and Friends. Seabury Press, N. Y. 1978
Thesis: Counseling the Male Homosexual. New York Theological Seminary Library 1969
Essay: Christopher Isherwood and the Religious Quest. The Gay Academic, an ETC Publication 1977
Papers: The Ethics of Transexualism. The convention of the American Psychological Association, New Orleans, La., Sept. 1974
Formation of a transsexual Group. Published in the Proceeding of the Fourth Interdisciplinary Symposium on Gender Dysphoria Syndrome, Stanford University, Calif. 1975
Follow-up of a Transsexual Group. Presented at the Fifth International Gender Dysphoria Symposium, Norfolk, Virginia 1977
Some Reflections on the Ethical, Moral Aspects of Sex Reassignment Surgery. The Sixth International Symposium on Gender Dysphoria, Coronado, Calif. 1979
Ministering to Sexual Minorities. Conference on Pastoral Approaches to Homosexuality - Pitlocry, Scotland 1980
Is Sex Reassignment Surgery Necessary? The Seventh International Symposium on Gender Dysphoria - University of Nevada - held at Lake Tahoe, Nevada 1981
Relationships After Cross Dressing. The Eighth International Symposium on Gender Dysphoria - The University of Bordeaux, France 1983
Heterosexual Marriage after Sex Reassignment Surgery. The Ninth International Symposium on Gender Dysphoria - The University Heterosexual Marriage after Sex Reassignment Surgery of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota 1985
Theological Questions and Pastoral Responses Regarding Gender Dysphoria - The Tenth International Symposium on Gender Dysphoria - The Free University, Amsterdam, The Netherlands
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged alphabetically, into two series:
Series I: Committee Files, which contain the records of the Henry Foundation's Rehabilitation Committee, Project "H", Committee on Sexual Minorities. Series II: Canon Clinton Jones Papers
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Scope and Content
The collection consist of minutes of meetings held between 1963 and 1982, reports, articles, annual reports, talks and newspaper clippings, and subject files kept by Canon Clinton Jones. Much of the committee correspondence consists of letters to and from Canon Clinton Jones. Among the correspondents are letters from Foster Gunnison Jr., a pioneer in the gay liberation movement. Mr. Gunnison headed the Institute of Social Ethics in Hartford. There are many letters from Alfred A. Gross, director of the George W. Henry Foundation in New York city. Materials about ERCHO (Eastern Regional Conference of Homophile Organizations) and NACHO (North American Conference of Homophile Organizations) are also present. The collection provides a wealth of historic information concerning all aspects of homosexuality and the gay liberation movement through the Stonewall riots and beyond.
Oral History Interview
An oral history interview of Canon Clinton Jones is available within the Digital Collections of the GLTBQ Archives on the website of the Elihu Burritt Library.
Gross, Alfred A; Gunnison, Foster; Jones, Clinton R; Administrative records.; Archival Material; Article; Correspondence.; Gay clergy; Gay rights.; Homosexuality -- United States.; Minutes.; Psychotherapy.; Speeches.; Typescripts
- Series I: Committee Files
  - REHABILITATION COMMITTEE, (FORERUNNER OF PROJECT "H"CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES), 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - PROJECT "H", CORRESPONDENCE, ETC., 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE, OCT. 1966 - JUNE 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE, JUNE 1967 - JUNE 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE, MINUTES, JUNE 1968 - JUNE 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE, JUNE 1969 THRU DEC. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE, JAN. 1970 THRU MAY 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE, JUNE. 1970 THRU DEC. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE, JAN. 1971 THRU MAY 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE, JUNE. 1971 THRU DEC. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JUNE. 1970 THRU DEC. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JAN. - JUNE 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, FEB. 1973 - JUNE 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JUNE 1973 - DEC. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JAN. 1974 - DEC. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JAN. - JUNE 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JULY. - DEC. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JAN. - JUNE 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JUNE - DEC. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JAN. - DEC 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JAN. 1978 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - PROJECT "H" CORRESPONDENCE & MINUTES, JAN. 1978 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - PROJECT "H" ARTICLES, SPEECHES, ADVERTISEMENTS, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - COMMITTEE ON SEXUAL MINORITIES, MINUTES, 1980 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - COMMITTEE ON SEXUAL MINORITIES, MINUTES, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - COMMITTEE ON SEXUAL MINORITIES, 1983 - 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - COMMITTEE ON SEXUAL MINORITIES, JAN. - DEC. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - COMMITTEE ON SEXUAL MINORITIES, JAN. 1985 - DEC. 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series II: Canon Clinton Jones Papers
  - A.A.S.E.C.T. AMERICAN ASSOCIATION OF SEX EDUCATORS AND THERAPISTS 1. DIRECTORY 2. 1982 BOOK OF ABSTRACTS (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ADVOCATE (FAIRFIELD) "FACES IN THE CROWD" BY JOHN MOTAVALL, JULY 28, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - AIDS EDUCATION (PAMPHLETS AND ARTICLES), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - AIDS MEMORIAL QUILT, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - AIDS MINISTRIES PROGRAM OF CONNECTICUT, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - ANNUAL REPORTS GEORGE W. HENRY FOUNDATION - HARTFORD, 1969 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "BATTLE OVER GAY RIGHTS" IN NEWSWEEK, JUNE 6, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - BAUM, GREGORY, "CATHOLIC HOMOSEXUALS" in COMMONWEAL, FEB 15, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - BERUBE, ALLAN, "COMING OUT UNDER FIRE" IN MOTHER JONES, FEB./MARCH 1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - BIBLIOGRAPHIES (1 0f 2) BIBLIOGRAPHIES ON HOMOSEXUALITY, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - BIBLIOGRAPHIES (2 of 2) BIBLIOGRAPHIES ON HOMOSEXUALITY (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - BOSTON/BOISE COMMITTEE, A REPORT TO THE COMMUNITY, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - BOYS WILL BE GIRLS: HIDDEN WORLD OF THE HETEROSEXUAL MALE TRANSVESTITE, BY JOHN T. TALAMINI, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - BROWN, KEITH, LOVE AGAINST LIFESTYLE 100 P. MANUSCRIPT, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - BURTON, JOHN DAVID, THE HOMOSEXUAL, A BIBLICAL VIEW, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - C.H.E., CAMPAIGN FOR HOMOSEXUAL EQUALITY PAMPHLET, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - CALDERWOOD, DERYCK "MASTURBATION, ABOUT YOUR SEXUALITY" BEAM PRESS, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - CANTOR, DONALD J., "DEVIATION AND THE CRIMINAL LAW" REPRINT FROM JOURNAL OF CRIMINAL LAW, CRIMINOLOGY AND POLICE SCIENCE, V.55 NO. 4, DEC. 1964 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - CARDINAL GRIFFIN REPORT, REPORT OF THE ROMAN CATHOLIC ADVISORY COMMITTEE ON HOMOSEXUAL OFFENCES, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - CATALOGUES BOOKSELLER'S CATALOGS, ELYSIAN FIELDS ARNO PRESS, PATHS UNTRODDEN, ALYSON, GLAD DAY BOOKSHOP, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CATALOGUES, INLAND BK CO, DIFFERENT LIGHT, POHLMAN PRESS, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - CATHOLIC CHURCH & HOMOSEXUALITY ARTICLES, 0197-1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - CAUSE FOR CONCERN THE CHRISTIAN CHURCH AND THE HOMOSEXUAL BY REV. DENNIS NADIN LONDON, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - CHRISTIAN CONDEMNATION OF HOMOSEXUALITY (ARTICLES AGAINST HOMOSEXUALITY), undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - CHURCH & THEOLOGY - articles, typescripts, 1964-1983 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    General note
    1. Task Group on Homosexuality and Ordination, 1983?
    2. Methodist Conference 1979 Statement on the Christian understanding of human sexuality
    3. Boswell, John St. Paul and homosexuality, talk 1970 4. "Issues raised by homosexuality a conversation between William Muehl and William Johnson" in Reflections v. 72 no. 4 May, 1975
    5. "To the pulpit or the pillory? Homosexual persons in the United Presbyterian Church" in Network News Witherpoon Society, Dec., 1976
    6. "Is the church ready?" by Nancy F. McConnell in Engage v.3. no 14. April 15, 1971
    7. "Homosexuality and the church" by James B. Nelson in Christianity & Crisis April 4, 1977
    8. Tull, Alan Condie, A response to Bennet J. Sims typescript, 27 p. Sept., 1978
    9. An introduction to the study of homosexuality and candidates for ordination to the ministry Presbyterian Church, 1976 typescript 12p. 1976?
    10. "Task group on the church and the gay community" University United Methodist Church, Madison, Wisconsin, typescript 10p. June, 1975
    11. Sex and Christian Responsibility. Institute Oct. 26, 1964
    12. Wood, Frederic C. "Sex within the created order" sermon Oct. 25, 1964 4p. typescript
  - CHURCH & THEOLOGY - articles, typescripts, 1966-1984 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    1. Macourt, Malcolm "Christians and gay liberation" One for Christian Renewal, Jan. 1978
    2. Grey, Anthony, Sex, morality and happiness. lecture, 1976
    3. Kirkpatrick, Bill "One Christian's attitudes to sexuality." talk, Dec. 1984
    4. Pittenger, Norman " A Christian's attitude to homosexuals." Address April 26, 1972
    5. Dutch Catholic statement on homosexuality, 1969
    6. Lutheran Church in America, Resolution on homosexuality July 2, 1970
    7. Unitarian University Association Resolution July 4, 1970
    8. Taylor, Clarke, "Gays and the church" in Blueboy 1974?
    9. Homophile League of Columbia University "we protest the Kolb panel" April 23, 1968
    10. Lucas, Donald S. "The homosexuals experience of the church" typescript n.d.
    11. Charles, Guy "The Gay Christian" in Logos Journal May/June 1976
    12. Chamberlain, Gary "Column" in The Critic, Mar. - April 1975
    13. Stemper, William H. "Liberal Protestants and Gay Sexuality: An Overview" in The Gay Academic Union Newsletter, no. 3 Aug. 1974, Hunter College, N. Y.
    14. Milam, Mary "My son is gay" typescript, 1970?
    15. Wink, Walter "Biblical perspectives on homosexuality" in The Christian Century. Nov. 7, 1979
    16. United Church of Christ "Resolution on homosexuals and the law" April 12, 1969
    17. Genne, William H. "The churches and sexuality" in Siecus Newsletter v. 2 no. 3, Fall 1966
  - COLLEGE OF PREACHERS, Material About a Conference on Ministry with the Gay and Lesbian Community, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "COMING OUT" IN CHRISTIANITY AND CRISIS. V. 39 NO. 10, JUNE 11, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - CONFERENCE, SCOTLAND, Pastoral Approaches To Homosexuality, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - CONNECTICUT ALUMNUS, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - CONSULTATION ON THEOLOGY AND THE HOMOSEXUAL, AUGUST 22 - 24, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - CROSS DRESSING, A SOCIO-CULTURAL SURVEY [BY] JOHN T. TALAMINI, Feb. 17, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - DE-LA-NOY, MICHAEL, "HOMOSEXUALITY: THE CHURCH'S RECORD" Reprint from Christian Renewal, Dec. 1971 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - TOUCHET FRANCIS H "A VIEW FROM THE OTHER SIDE OF THE GARDEN" (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - DIGNITY CONSTITUTION, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "DISCRIMINATION AGAINST THE EMPLOYMENT OF HOMOSEXUALS", STATEMENT PREPARED BY THE MATTACHINE SOCIETY OF WASHINGTON, D.C., FEB. 28, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - EDWARDS, SARAH A., THE BIBLE SAYS. HOMOSEXUALITY... AN EXEGETICAL EXPLORATION typescript, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - THE EFFECTS OF LARGE NUMBERS OF DEATHS ON INDIVIDUALS AND THEIR COMMUNITY - AIDS AND THE COMMUNITY, Report, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - EPISCOPALIAN, Issues of, Nov. 1997 and Feb 1982 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - EPISCOPAL CHURCH AND HOMOSEXUALITY, 1967-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    1. Campbell, Ernest T. "Overheard in Room 738" in Sermons from Riverside, Feb. 17, 1974
    2. "Love of the Brethren, The Christian homosexual" sermon by Joseph Upson, June, 28, 1970
    3. Doubleday, William A. "A perspective on the ordination of homosexual persons in the Episcopal Church" typescript April 28, 1979
    4. Diocese of Maryland, Committee on human sexuality in the church, report May, 1979
    5. Coffin, William S. "Homosexuality" a sermon August 12, 1981
    6. Kennedy, James A. "A testament of faith & a farewell, Sermon Mar. 25, 1973 typescript
    7. "Ministry to the homosexual" in The Living Church by Rev. R. W. Cromey, Jan. 8, 1967
    8. Rash John "Reforming pastoral attitudes toward homosexuality" reprint from Union Seminary Quarterly Review, Summer 1970
    9. King's Ministries (Episcopal) News serial issues,1977
    10. Crew, Louie "View from a gay person's pew" in The Witness, 1983
    11. Boyd, Malcom, "On Bishop Tutu, gays, Christians and belonging together" in The Witness, Dec. 1986
    12. York, Richard "The institutions of Marriage and Family and Evil" paper Sept. 1979
  - ESSAYS ON SEXUALITY, 6 essays on aspects of sexuality, Trinity College, Hartford, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - FANTASIA FAIR, Transsexual program, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - FEHREN, HENRY, "A CHRISTIAN RESPONSE TO HOMOSEXUALS" reprint from US Catholic, Sept. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - FINK, PETER E., "HOMOSEXUALITY, A PASTORAL HYPOTHESIS" reprint from Commonweal, April 6, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - FOSTER, ARTHUR L., "A PASTORAL THEOLOGIAN LOOKS AT HOMOSEXUALITY", undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - GAY ACTIVISTS ALLIANCE, "LIST OF GAY ORGANIZATIONS", no. 3, FEB, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - G.C.M.,GAY CHRISTIAN MOVEMENT, LONDON pamphlets, flyers, working papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - GAY CHRISTIAN MOVEMENT LONDON, ANNUAL REPORT, 1984, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - GAY FLAMES (DUPLICATE) articles, poems, drawings, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - GAY MEN'S HEALTH CRISIS, PROGRAM FOR CIRCUS FUNDRAISER, APRIL 30, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - GAY OPPRESSION AND LIBERATION OR: HOMOPHOBIA: ITS CAUSES AND CURE. by Gay Theory Work Group, June, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - GAY RIGHTS NATIONAL LOBBY, Flyers, bulletins, letters, 1977, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - GAY USA (FILM REVIEW), SEPT. 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "GAYS IN THE CHURCH SPEAK FOR THEMSELVES" IN THE WITNESS, OCT. 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - GEORGE W. HENRY FOUNDATION, NEW YORK, ANNUAL REPORTS, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - GEORGE W. HENRY FOUNDATION, CONNECTICUT, BIBLIOGRAPHY (LIBRARY), 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - GOOD, CANDY HOMOSEXUALITY, REPORT TYPESCRIPT, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - GREENGRASS, MARTIN J., "PROPOSAL FOR THE TREATMENT OF PEDOPHILES AND OTHER SEXUAL DEVIATES", includes questionaire to be Used in the Connecticut Correction Institution, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - GREY, ANTONY CHRISTIAN SOCIETY AND THE HOMOSEXUAL, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "AMERICAN EXPERIMENT" IN MAN AND SOCIETY, no. 10, WINTER 1966, Abbreviated version of a talk delivered Oct. 16, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - GROSS, ALFRED "THE AMERICAN HOMOPHILE MOVEMENT", Address, Dec. 5, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "THE CHURCH'S MISSION TO THE SEXUALLY DEVIATED", Address, NOV. 23, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "THE CHURCH'S MISSION TO THE SEXUALITY DEVIATED", JAN. 17, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "THE CHURCH AND THE HOMOSEXUAL" Being a revision (Oct., 1978) of A Nov. 1964, Address (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "DEMYTHOLOGIZING THE HOMOSEXUAL" Address originally prepared for delivery in the summer of 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "ETHICAL ASPECTS OF THE PROBLEM OF HOMOSEXUALITY" ADDRESS, typescript published in v. 11 Oct. 1967 issue of St. Lukes Journal (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. THE ETHICAL DILEMMA, AN ADDRESS, typescript, JAN., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. EX ORE HERETICI, From v. 1 no. 4 July - Aug. 1972 ISSUE OF THE GAY CHRISTIAN (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "A HALF CENTURY OF ANGLICANISM", undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "THE HOMOPHILE MOVEMENT", (LECTURE) DRAFT, DEC. 5, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "THE HOMOPHILE MOVEMENT" DEC. 5, 1967 - ADDRESS (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "HOMOSEXUAL'S PROGRESS" Address, JULY 19, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. The Presistant Problem of The Homosexual.., A Social Approach Paper Read Before The Charlotte, N.C., Mental Hygiene society, January 30th, 1956 in Psychological Service Center Journal v.9, JULY 19, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 33a)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "HOMOSEXUAL IN HOLY ORDERS" typescript, Dec., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "IS HOMOSEXUALITY A MINORITY PROBLEM" An address, APRIL 18, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "IS THERE A SANTA CLAUS? A DISCOURSE", March 25, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. LOOKING BACKWARD AND FORWARD An Address, MARCH 25, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "LUX IN TENEBRIS" AN ADDRESS, NOVEMBER 14, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "A MINORITY BECOMES ARTICULATE " A Lecture, April 13, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "MISFITS IN THE GREAT SOCIETY?" AN ADDRESS, November 5, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. OF PROPHETS AND PRIESTS, A SERMON, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "QHO VADIS?" A sermon, February 15, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "SOCIAL FACTORS IN THE CASE HISTORIES OF ONE HUNDRED UNDER-PRIVILEGED HOMOSEXUALS" IN v. 22 no 4, Mental Hygiene, October 1938 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. SOMETHING ABOUT HERESY", AN ADDRESS, April, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "TELL IT LIKE IT IS" A SERMON, March 15, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "THESIS, ANTITHESIS, SYNTHESIS" An Address, May 31, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "A TRACT FOR THE TIMES" Paper read Oct. 22, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "A TRACT FOR THE TIMES" ADDRESS MARLBORO COLLEGE COMMENCEMENT, June, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "WASTED LIVES IN THE PROMISED LAND" An Address, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - GROSS, ALFRED A. "WHAT PRICE FREEDOM" A Sermon, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - HAGIUS, HUGH THE MYSTERY OF A SCARLET PANSY. AN UNDERGOUND GAY NOVEL OF THE LOST GENERATION typescript, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - HECHINGER, GRACE, "HOMOSEXUALITY ON CAMPUS" ... IN N.Y. TIMES MAGAZINE, March 12, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - HOMOPHILE MOVEMENT -- 1940'S and 1950'S, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - HOMOPHILE MOVEMENT -- 1960'S, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
    1.Grey, Antony, "Homosexuality and sexual deviancy in London",A Talk Nov. 18, 1969
    2.Janus Society newsletter
    3.Hairpin drop heard around the world, June 1969 (About the Stonewall riot.)
    4. One, Calendar of events
    5. "Is homosexuality a sickness?" 1965
    6. Corduroy Club
    7. Friends, Homosexuality 1968
    8. Spectrum newsletter
  - HOMOPHILE MOVEMENT -- 1960'S, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    1. Cantor, Donald J. "The homosexual revolution a status report" in the Humanist, Sept./Dec. 1967
    2. Talks given at 2nd National Planning Conference of Homophile Organizations (NACHO) San Francisco August 25, 1966 including Foster Gunnision's "Three concrete steps to further the homophile movement"
    3. 1968 annual report of the Institute for the Study of Human Resources
    4. Second National Planning Conference of Homophile Organizations (NACHO) 1966, Actions Taken
  - HOMOPHILE MOVEMENT -- 1960'S and 1970'S Flyers, pamphlets, The Swinger, New Britain, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - HOMOPHILE MOVEMENT -- 1970'S, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
    1. Smedes, Lewis B. "Homosexuality, sorting out the issues" in the Reformed Journal, Jan 1978
    2. Lyon, Phyllis "Homosexuals are persons" in Spectrum, Nov. - Dec. 1971